Michael HINTON

www.coderfoundry.com/michaelhinton

FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript/ES6 JQuery Bootstrap .NET C# MVC ASP.NET

> LINQ Xamarin WebAPI

SOL & Bash

CODER FOUNDRY

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284 (336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

EDUCATION

Winston-Salem State University, B.A. Fine Arts - Digital Concentration Winston-Salem, NC · 2015

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Coder Foundry, Web Software Engineer

Kernersville, NC · October 2019–December 2019

- Created three primary projects, including:
 - 1. A portfolio site using C#, MVC, HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP, JS & jQuery.
 - 2. A Financial Portal implemented in three phases. Phase 1: an MVC Web Application, Phase 2: a Web Service that utilizes Swagger and Swashbuckle for integrated testing, Phase 3: A cross platform Xamarin Mobile Application.
 - 3. Fully designed and developed a multi-functional issue tracker web application, implementing enhanced roles & security, which also used a Code First Relational database designed and modeled in SQL Server. Technologies used include: .Net Framework v. 4.6.1, MVC5, C#, LINQ, SQL, Entity Framework, jQuery DataTables.

Herbalife Manufacturing, Forklift Operator

Winston-Salem, NC · December 2017–October 2019

- Operated in filler room, overseeing tea distribution in bottles, signing off on paper work, troubleshooting any issues with tea dispensers.
- Uses oracle scanner for locating, moving, unpacking, packing and sub-transferring inventory.

Lifetouch Portrait Studios, Photographer

Kernersville, NC · August 2016-March 2017

Took staff and student pictures for various schools in the piedmont area.